Raghu Chaitanya (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Release Management, Configuration Management, Software Installation, Software Troubleshooting, Project Management, Quality Assurance, Root Cause Analysis, Shell Scripting, JIRA, SQL Server, Maven, Jenkins, Servicenow



Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Hyderabad Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Maintenance

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Role: Software Developer

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Release Management, Configuration Management, Software

Installation, Software Troubleshooting, Project Management, Quality Assurance, Root Cause Analysis, Shell

Scripting, JIRA, SQL Server, Maven, Jenkins, Servicenow

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

4.8 years of IT experience in Build & Release Management, DevOps implementations and Attlasian tools administration(jira, confluence, bitbucket, fisheye, crucible).

Provide assistance to clients with the implementation of configuration management, release management and process creation.

Experienced in planning, installation, administration of Subversion, GIT on Linux and Windows platforms.

Experienced in implementing CI pipelines in GitLab using Maven Ansible and Sonar.

Experienced in implementation of CI/CD pipelines, managing projects often includes build tracking ultiple deployments across multiple pipeline stages (Dev, QA, UAT and Production).

Good working experience to deploying and hosting of the applications on Linux, Windows platforms.

Experience in migrating applications repositories from Subversion to GIT.

Extensive experience on build tools Ant, Maven.

Experience on Code review tool Sonar.

Good experience on Continuous Integration tools like Jenkins and AnthillPro.

Work Experience

Dell as Senior Software Engineer Nov 2019 to May 2020

Attlasian tool stack service desk engineer

HCL Technologies Private Limited as Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2016 to Nov 2019

Project #1:

Project : Deal Management System

Client: TullettPrebon, UK

: DevOps, Release Management Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Tools: Windows, Linux, GIT, Maven, Jenkins, Jboss, Shell Scripting, Jira, Sonar

: May 2016 Till Date Duration

Description:

Deal Management System (DMS) provide post trade functions for Tullett prebon. Once trade is executed, it is validated

and enriched by DMS with additional information such as brokerage allocations & settlement instructions and then persisted in its own database. These deals are presented to users through DMS GUI for approval and amendments. Once approval process is completed DMS orchestrate further activities mediated by downstream system (TMM) for STP, reporting and confirmation.

Project# 2:

Project : Tradeblade Client : TulletPrebon, UK

Roles : SCM, Build & Release Engineering

Tools : Windows, Linux, Svn, Ant, AnthillPro, Apache Tomcat, Jboss, Jira, Shell Scripting.

Duration: May 2016 Till Date

Description:

The Tullet Prebon business provides customers with inter dealer broker (IDB) services that support the execution of over the counter (OTC) interest rate derivative transactions. Both the Tullett Prebon and customer entities are located in a variety of financial centers across the world. The TP services allow traders at customer organizations to anonymously make known the details of their trading intentions (orders) to other participants in the market. Each participant is also made aware of the orders that TP have received from other market participants.

Responsibilities:

Experienced in DevOps Engineer for different project that involved different development teams and multiple simultaneous environment releases.

Developed and implemented Software Release Management strategies for various applications according to the agile process.

Analyzing the E2E requirements and provide the low-level design.

Participated in weekly release meetings with Technology stakeholders to identify and mitigate risks associated with the releases.

Extensive exposure to Configuration Management policies and practices with regards to SDLC; along with automation of scripting using BASH/Shell scripting.

Created continuous integration system using Ant, AnthillPro and shell script for Continuous Integration, faster and flawless deployments.

Created CI pipelines in GitLab server using Maven, Sonar and Cobertura.

Responsible for Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Delivery (CD) process implementation using Jenkins along with Shell scripts to automate routine jobs.

Implemented quality release of Applications and solutions for Delivery Manager.

Worked in migrating code from SVN to Git server (GitLab), clean the git repo (purging files).

Implemented branching strategies by following git default workflow.

Worked on build tasks using Maven, Ant to automate the build process.

Imported and managed multiple corporate applications in Subversion (SVN).

Worked on Maven to create artifacts from source code and deploy them in Nexus central repository to manage multi module build dependencies.

Integrated Jenkins with various DevOps tools such as Git, Maven, shell scripts, Nexus, SonarQube etc.

Worked as admin for Atlassian tools like Confluence, Jira, Hipchat.

End-user training regarding branching strategies for all Subversion (SVN) users to effectively use the tool.

Created sonar reports for different non-prod environments to ensure quality of the software released to higher environments.

Used Jenkins for enterprise scale infrastructure configuration and application deployments.

Performed dispatcher role to distribute tasks assigned to the onshore team.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from JNTU College of Engineering, Kakinada in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Windows, Linux, Svn, Ant, AnthillPro	
Microsoft Office	
Apache Tomcat, Jboss, Jira, Shell Script	
MAVEN	
Linux, Windows	

SONAR		
SQL Server, Oracle		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

Projects

Project Title: Deal Management System

Client: TullettPrebon, UK

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2016 - Nov 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Deal Management System (DMS) provide post trade functions for Tullett prebon. Once trade is executed, it is validated and enriched by DMS with additional information such as brokerage allocations & settlement instructions and then persisted in its own database. These deals are presented to users through DMS GUI for approval and amendments. Once approval process is completed DMS orchestrate further activities mediated by downstream system (TMM) for STP, reporting and confirmation.

Project Title: Tradeblade Client: TulletPrebon, UK

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2016 - Nov 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The Tullet Prebon business provides customers with inter dealer broker (IDB) services that support the execution of over the counter (OTC) interest rate derivative transactions. Both the Tullett Prebon and customer entities are located in a variety of financial centers across the world. The TP services allow traders at customer organizations to anonymously make known the details of their trading intentions (orders) to other participants in the market. Each participant is also made aware of the orders that TP have received from other market participants.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Employment Status: Full time

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent